Ian Hill

State College, PA

Phone: (814) 280-7652 | Email: ian@ianahill.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ian-hill-9019911a0 | Portfolio: www.ianahill.com

Summary

Full-stack web developer and former Lutheran pastor with nearly ten years of experience using web technologies to help an organization realize its mission. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from Rutgers Coding Bootcamp. Known as a team player with strengths in server-side development, databases, and oral and written communication.

Technical Skills

 $\textbf{Browser Based Technologies:} \ \textbf{HTML/CSS, JavaScript, responsive design, React.js, WordPress, Redux}$

Server-Side Development: MERN stack, user authentication, databases (MySQL, MongoDB)

API Design: Rest, JSON, AJAX (Fetch API), HTTP request methods, GraphQL

Projects

Family Cookbook | www.github.com/Zzaclipse/familyCookbook | family-cookbook-astokes.herokuapp.com/

- A cloud-based cookbook that stores treasured family recipes for easy sharing and access
- My role was focused mostly on server development, writing API routes to the database
- Utilized HTML/CSS, JavaScript, node.js, express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Cloudinary, Bootstrap

Slice N' Dice | www.github.com/clogerie92/Slice-n-Dice | link to deployed app (not deployed yet)

- A fictional pizza restaurant's ordering and delivery app
- My core responsibilities were focused on developing the front-end and GraphQL API
- Utilized React.js, GraphQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, MongoDB

Experience

Full-stack Developer, The House Next Door, Princeton NJ

2022-Current

Developed front-end website and fully functioning database from scratch for a non-profit organization.

- Developed and maintains website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Developed and maintains event database in MySQL
- Created and maintains server using Express and RESTful API

Pastor, St. Mark Lutheran Church, Hamilton NJ

2014-2022

Managed many projects while collaborating with a variety of teams, which allowed us to provide vital services to the community. Contributed regular written reports and public presentations to provide accountability and organization across teams. Developed and maintained website, social media, and email marketing, resulting in increased engagement and web presence.

Key Accomplishments:

- Developed organization's website from scratch, including a responsive, modern design
- Successfully rebranded the organization, which increased exposure and social media following.

Education

Full-stack Web-Development Certificate: Rutgers University, New Brunswick NJ **Master of Divinity:** Lutheran Theological Seminary at Philadelphia, Philadelphia PA **Bachelor of Arts, Anthropology:** Pennsylvania State University, State College PA

2022 2010-2014

2003-2007